# HIMANSHU SONI

# QA Engineer – Automation and Manual Testing – SDET

# PROFESSIONAL STATEMENT

Motivated and highly adaptable QA professional with over 10 years of experience in automation and manual testing. ISTQB (International Software Testing Qualifications Board) foundation level certified. Comprehensive experience in functional and regression testing of Web Application, and REST APIs. Experience in software development lifecycle, software test lifecycle and Agile (Scrum) Methodology. Proven ability to deliver quality product on time. One-month onsite experience to work with Product Definition and Dev teams in Nice, France.

# **PROFILE**

#### Name:

Himanshu Soni

#### Location:

Bengaluru, KA, India

# Phone:

+91-7829284424

#### Email:

eng.sonihimanshu@gmail.com

# **SKILLS**

#### Tools:

Selenium WebDriver, SoapUI (REST services), Junit, TestNG, GIT, Jenkins, Maven, HP ALM, JIRA

**Programming Languages:** Java Core, SQL

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Amadeus Software Labs, Bengaluru, India

Member Technical Staff QA

Apr 2019 - Current

Senior QA Engineer (SDET)

Aug 2014 - Mar 2019

- Design automation framework for web applications using Selenium WebDriver in Java language.
- Design automation test suite for back-end validations of REST APIs in SoapUI.
- Configure automation framework, test scripts in Jenkins for scheduled run, and publish test execution report.
- Involved in requirement analysis, manage test plan, test case design, automated test framework design, design review, requirement mapping with tests.
- Report and track software defects through HP ALM
- Coordinate with Development and BA teams to track, review, re-produce and analyze defects.
- Publish weekly and monthly reports providing a high-level overview of test execution status, defects and blockers to higher management and clients.
- Assist team members in troubleshooting problems, implementing QA practices and provide application knowledge.
- Actively contribute in sprint planning and give collaborative QA sizing for the user stories.

# Accenture Services Private Limited, Bengaluru, India

Software Engineering Analyst
Associate Software Engineer

Apr 2011 - Aug 2014

Apr 2010 - Mar 2011

- Replicate the DSL, Dial, Broadband orders in test systems through Siebel CRM and validate End-To-End process of order flow through the entire cycle, covering the complete order journey starting from Operations Support System (OSS) to Business Support System (BSS).
- Generate the blue prints of telecom services bills in test system using UNIX shell scripts and validate the results in DB using SQL queries.
- Automated OneKPN customer care portal using Selenium WebDriver.
- Perform sanity tests by sending requests to back end APIs through SoapUI to validate that all the services are up and running in Test systems.
- Add and fix test scripts in regression suite.

# **EDUCATION**

Rajiv Gandhi Technical University, Bhopal, MP, India

B.E. in Electronics and Communications Engineering

Aug 2005 – Jun 2009